    <!-- ======================================================== 4 -->
    <section anchor="background" title="Background">

      <t>At the time the IPPM WG was chartered, sound Bulk
      Transport Capacity (BTC) measurement was known to be well beyond
      our capabilities. Even at the time that Framework for Empirical 
      BTC Metrics 
      <xref target="RFC3148" /> was written we knew that we didn't
      fully understand the problem. Now, by hindsight we understand
      why assessing BTC is such a hard problem:
      <list style="symbols">

        <t>TCP is a control system with circular dependencies -
        everything affects performance, including components that
        are explicitly not part of the test (for example, the host 
        processing power is not in-scope of path performance tests).</t>

        <t>Congestion control is a dynamic equilibrium process,
	similar to processes observed in chemistry and other fields.
        The network and transport protocols find an operating point
	which balances between opposing forces:
	the transport protocol pushing harder
	(raising the data rate and or window)
	while the network pushes back
	(raising packet loss ratio, RTT and/or ECN CE marks).
        By design TCP congestion control keeps
        raising the data rate until the network gives some
        indication that its capacity has been exceeded by dropping 
        packets or ECN CE marks. If a TCP sender accurately fills a
	path to its IP capacity, (e.g. the bottleneck is 100% utilized),
        then packet losses and ECN CE marks are mostly determined by 
        the TCP sender and how aggressively it seeks additional capacity,
        and not the network itself, since the network
	must send exactly the signals that TCP needs to set its rate.</t>

        <t>TCP's ability to compensate for network impairments (such as 
        loss, delay and delay variation, outside of those caused by TCP 
        itself) is directly proportional to the number of send-ACK round trip
        exchanges per second (i.e. inversely proportional to the RTT). As a
        consequence an impaired subpath may pass a short RTT local test even
        though it fails when the subpath is extended by an effectively 
        perfect network to some larger RTT.</t>

        <t>TCP has an extreme form of the Observer Effect
	(colloquially know as the Heisenberg effect).
        Measurement and cross traffic interact in unknown and ill
        defined ways.
        The situation is actually worse than the
        traditional physics problem where you can at least estimate
        bounds on the relative momentum of the measurement and
        measured particles. For network measurement you can not in
        general determine even the order of magnitude of the effect.
	It is possible to construct measurement scenarios where
	the measurement traffic starves real user traffic, yielding
	an overly inflated measurement.  The inverse is also possible:
	the user traffic can fill the network, such that the
	measurement traffic detects only minimal available capacity.
	You can not in general determine which scenario might be
	in effect, so you can not gauge the
        relative magnitude of the uncertainty that is
        introduced by interactions with other network traffic.</t>

        <t>It is difficult, if not impossible, for two independent
        implementations (HW or  SW) of TCP congestion control to produce 
        equivalent performance results <xref target="RFC6576" />
        under the same network conditions, as an outcome of the
        other properties listed. </t>
      </list></t>

      <t>These properties are a consequence of the dynamic equilibrium
      behavior intrinsic to how all throughput maximizing protocols
      interact with the Internet. These protocols rely on control
      systems based on estimated network metrics to regulate the
      quantity of data sent into the network. The packet sending 
      characteristics in turn alter the network properties
      estimated by the control system metrics, such that there are 
      circular dependencies between every transmission characteristic
      and every estimated metric. Since some of these dependencies
      are nonlinear, the entire system is nonlinear, and any change 
      causes a response in packet sending characteristics or
      estimated network metrics that is difficult to predict.</t>

      <t>Model Based Metrics overcome these problems by making the
      measurement system open loop: the packet transfer statistics
      (akin to the network estimators) do not affect the traffic or
      traffic patterns (bursts), which are computed on the basis of the
      Target Transport Performance. A path or subpath meeting the Target 
      Transfer Performance requirements would exhibit packet transfer 
      statistics and estimated metrics that would not cause the control
      system to slow the traffic below the Target Data Rate.</t>
      <section anchor="tcp" title="TCP properties">

        <t>TCP and SCTP are self clocked protocols that carry the
        vast majority of all Internet data. Their dominant behavior
        is to have an approximately fixed quantity of data and
        acknowledgments (ACKs) circulating in the network. The
        data receiver reports arriving data by returning ACKs to
        the data sender, the data sender typically responds by
        sending exactly the same quantity of data back into the
        network. The total quantity of data plus the data
        represented by ACKs circulating in the network is referred
        to as the window. The mandatory congestion control
        algorithms incrementally adjust the window by sending
        slightly more or less data in response to each ACK. The
        fundamentally important property of this system is that it
        is self clocked: The data transmissions are a reflection of
        the ACKs that were delivered by the network, the ACKs are a
        reflection of the data arriving from the network.</t>

        <t>A number of protocol features cause bursts of data, even
        in idealized networks that can be modeled as simple
        queuing systems.</t>

        <t>During slowstart the IP rate is doubled on each RTT by
        sending twice as much data as was delivered to the receiver
        during the prior RTT. Each returning ACK causes the sender
        to transmit twice the data the ACK reported arriving at the
        receiver. For slowstart to be able to fill the pipe, the
        network must be able to tolerate slowstart bursts up to the
        full pipe size inflated by the anticipated window reduction
        on the first loss or ECN CE mark. For example, with classic
        Reno congestion control, an optimal slowstart has to end
        with a burst that is twice the bottleneck rate for one RTT
        in duration. This burst causes a queue which is equal to
        the pipe size (i.e. the window is twice the pipe size) so
        when the window is halved in response to the first packet
        loss, the new window will be the pipe size.</t>

        <t>Note that if the bottleneck IP rate is less that half of
        the capacity of the front path (which is almost always the
        case), the slowstart bursts will not by themselves cause
        significant queues anywhere else along the front path; they
        primarily exercise the queue at the dominant
        bottleneck.</t>

        <t>Several common efficiency algorithms also cause bursts.
        The self clock is typically applied to groups of packets:
        the receiver's delayed ACK algorithm generally sends only
        one ACK per two data segments. Furthermore the modern
        senders use TCP segmentation offload (TSO) to reduce CPU
        overhead. The sender's software stack builds super sized TCP
        segments that the TSO hardware splits into MTU sized
        segments on the wire. The net effect of TSO, delayed ACK
        and other efficiency algorithms is to send bursts of
        segments at full sender interface rate.</t>

        <t>Note that these efficiency algorithms are almost always
        in effect, including during slowstart, such that slowstart
        typically has a two level burst structure. 
        <xref target="paced" /> describes slowstart in more
        detail.</t>

        <t>Additional sources of bursts include TCP's initial
        window 
        <xref target="RFC6928" />, application pauses, channel
        allocation mechanisms and network devices that schedule
        ACKs. 
        <xref target="complex" /> describes these last two items. If
        the application pauses (stops reading or writing data) for
        some fraction of an RTT, many TCP implementations catch up
        to their earlier window size by sending a burst of data at
        the full sender interface rate. To fill a network with a
        realistic application, the network has to be able to
        tolerate sender interface rate bursts large enough to
        restore the prior window following application pauses.</t>

        <t>Although the sender interface rate bursts are typically
        smaller than the last burst of a slowstart, they are at a
        higher IP rate so they potentially exercise queues at
        arbitrary points along the front path from the data sender
        up to and including the queue at the dominant bottleneck.
        There is no model for how frequent or what sizes of sender
        rate bursts the network should tolerate.</t>

        <t>In conclusion, to verify that a path can meet a Target
        Transport Performance, it is necessary to independently
        confirm that the path can tolerate bursts at the scales
        that can be caused by the above mechanisms. Three cases are
        believed to be sufficient:</t>

        <t>
          <list style="symbols">

            <t>Two level slowstart bursts sufficient to get
            connections started properly.</t>

            <t>Ubiquitous sender interface rate bursts caused by
            efficiency algorithms. We assume 4 packet bursts to be
            the most common case, since it matches the effects of
            delayed ACK during slowstart. These bursts should be
            assumed not to significantly affect packet transfer
            statistics.</t>

            <t>Infrequent sender interface rate bursts that are
            full target_window_size. Target_run_length may be
            derated for these large fast bursts.</t>
          </list>
        </t>

        <t>If a subpath can meet the required packet loss ratio for
        bursts at all of these scales then it has sufficient
        buffering at all potential bottlenecks to tolerate any of
        the bursts that are likely introduced by TCP or other
        transport protocols.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="approach" title="Diagnostic Approach">
        <!--

<t>Reinstate? @@@@   Therefore each subpath's contribution to the end-to-end packet transfer statistics can be assumed to be independent, and spatial composition techniques such as <xref target="RFC5835" /> and <xref target="RFC6049" /> apply. </t> -->

        <t>A complete path of a given RTT and MTU, which are equal
        to or smaller than the Target RTT and equal to or larger
        than the Target MTU respectively, is expected to be able to
        attain a specified Bulk Transport Capacity when all of the
        following conditions are met:
        <list style="numbers">

          <t>The IP capacity is above the Target Data Rate by
          sufficient margin to cover all TCP/IP overheads. This can
          be confirmed by the tests described in 
          <xref target="basicdata" /> or any number of IP capacity
          tests adapted to implement MBM.</t>

          <t>The observed packet transfer statistics are better
          than required by a suitable TCP performance model (e.g.
          fewer packet losses or ECN CE marks). See 
          <xref target="basicdata" /> or any number of low rate
          packet loss tests outside of MBM.</t>

          <t>There is sufficient buffering at the dominant
          bottleneck to absorb a slowstart bursts large enough to
          get the flow out of slowstart at a suitable window size.
          See 
          <xref target="slowstart" />.</t>

          <t>There is sufficient buffering in the front path to
          absorb and smooth sender interface rate bursts at all
          scales that are likely to be generated by the
          application, any channel arbitration in the ACK path or
          any other mechanisms. See 
          <xref target="sender_rate" />.</t>

          <t>When there is a slowly rising standing queue at the
          bottleneck the onset of packet loss has to be at an
          appropriate point (time or queue depth) and progressive 
          <xref target="RFC7567" />. See 
          <xref target="standing_queue" />.</t>

          <t>When there is a standing queue at a bottleneck for a
          shared media subpath (e.g. half duplex), there must be a
          suitable bounds on the interaction between ACKs and data,
          for example due to the channel arbitration mechanism. See
          
          <xref target="self_interference" />.</t>
        </list></t>

        <t>Note that conditions 1 through 4 require capacity tests
        for validation, and thus may need to be monitored on an
        ongoing basis. Conditions 5 and 6 require engineering
        tests, which are best performed in controlled environments
        such as a bench test. They won't generally fail due to
        load, but may fail in the field due to configuration
        errors, etc. and should be spot checked.</t>

        <t>We are developing a tool that can perform many of the
        tests described here 
        <xref target="MBMSource" />.</t>
        <!-- @@ move? -->
      </section>
      <section anchor="requirements"
      title="New requirements relative to RFC 2330">

        <t>Model Based Metrics are designed to fulfill some
        additional requirements that were not recognized at the
        time RFC 2330 was written 
        <xref target="RFC2330" />. These missing requirements may
        have significantly contributed to policy difficulties in
        the IP measurement space. Some additional requirements are:
        <list style="symbols">

          <t>IP metrics must be actionable by the ISP - they have
          to be interpreted in terms of behaviors or properties at
          the IP or lower layers, that an ISP can test, repair and
          verify.</t>

          <t>Metrics should be spatially composable, such that
          measures of concatenated paths should be predictable from
          subpaths. 
          <!-- Ideally they should also be differentiable: the metrics of a subpath should be  @@ oops  --></t>

          <t>Metrics must be vantage point invariant over a
          significant range of measurement point choices, including
          off path measurement points. The only requirements on MP
          selection should be that the RTT between the MPs is below
          some reasonable bound, and that the effects of the "test
          leads" connecting MPs to the subpath under test can be
          can be calibrated out of the measurements. The latter
          might be be accomplished if the test leads are
          effectively ideal or their properties can be deducted
          from the measurements between the MPs. While many of
          tests require that the test leads have at least as much
          IP capacity as the subpath under test, some do not, for
          example Background Packet Transfer Tests described in 
          <xref target="backloss" />.</t>

          <t>Metric measurements should be repeatable by multiple
          parties with no specialized access to MPs or diagnostic
          infrastructure.
          It should be possible for different parties
          to make the same measurement and observe the same
          results. In particular it is specifically important that
          both a consumer (or their delegate) and ISP be able to
          perform the same measurement and get the same result.
          Note that vantage independence is key to meeting this
          requirement.</t>
        </list></t>
      </section>
    </section>
