      <section anchor="channelized"
      title="Concurrent or channelized testing">

        <t>The procedures described in this document are only
        directly applicable to single stream measurement, e.g. one
        TCP connection or measurement stream. In an ideal world, we
        would disallow all performance claims based multiple
        concurrent streams, but this is not practical due to at
        least two different issues. First, many very high rate link
        technologies are channelized and at last partially pin the
        flow to channel mapping to minimize packet reordering
        within flows. Second, TCP itself has scaling limits.
        Although the former problem might be overcome through
        different design decisions, the later problem is more
        deeply rooted.</t>

        <t>All congestion control algorithms that are
        philosophically aligned with the standard 
        <xref target="RFC5681" /> (e.g. claim some level of TCP
        compatibility, friendliness or fairness) have scaling
        limits, in the sense that as a long fast network (LFN) with
        a fixed RTT and MTU gets faster, these congestion control
        algorithms get less accurate and as a consequence have
        difficulty filling the network <xref target="CCscaling" />.
        These properties are a
        consequence of the original Reno AIMD congestion control
        design and the requirement in 
        <xref target="RFC5681" /> that all transport protocols have
        similar responses to congestion.</t>

        <t>There are a number of reasons to want to specify
        performance in term of multiple concurrent flows, however
        this approach is not recommended for data rates below
        several megabits per second, which can be attained with run
        lengths under 10000 packets on many paths. Since the
        required run length goes as the square of the data rate, at
        higher rates the run lengths can be unreasonably large, and
        multiple flows might be the only feasible approach.</t>

        <t>If multiple flows are deemed necessary to meet aggregate
        performance targets then this MUST be stated both the
        design of the TIDS and in any claims about network
        performance. The IP diagnostic tests MUST be performed
        concurrently with the specified number of connections. For
        the the tests that use bursty test streams, the bursts
        should be synchronized across streams.</t>
      </section>
