    <!-- ======================================================== 1. -->
    <section anchor="introduction" title="Introduction">

      <t>Model Based Metrics (MBM) rely on peer-reviewed
      mathematical models to
      specify a Targeted Suite of IP Diagnostic tests, designed to
      assess whether common transport protocols can be expected to
      meet a predetermined Target Transport Performance over an
      Internet path. This note describes the modeling framework to
      derive the test parameters for assessing an Internet path's
      ability to support a predetermined Bulk Transport
      Capacity.</t>

      <t>Each test in the Targeted IP Diagnostic Suite (TIDS)
      measures some aspect of IP packet transfer needed to meet the
      Target Transport Performance. For Bulk Transport Capacity the
      TIDS includes IP diagnostic tests to verify that there is:
      sufficient IP capacity (data rate); sufficient queue space at
      bottlenecks to absorb and deliver typical transport bursts;
      and that the background packet loss ratio is low enough not
      to interfere with congestion control; and other properties
      described below. Unlike typical IPPM metrics which yield
      measures of network properties, Model Based Metrics nominally
      yield pass/fail evaluations of the ability of standard 
      transport protocols to meet the specific performance
      objective over some network path.</t>

      <t>In most cases, the IP diagnostic tests can be implemented
      by combining existing IPPM metrics with additional controls
      for generating test streams having a specified temporal
      structure (bursts or standing queues caused by constant 
      bit rate streams, etc.) and statistical
      criteria for evaluating packet transfer. The temporal
      structure of the test streams mimic transport protocol
      behavior over the complete path; the statistical criteria
      models the transport protocol's response to less than ideal
      IP packet transfer.</t>

      <t>This note addresses Bulk Transport Capacity.  It
      describes an alternative to the approach
      presented in "A Framework for Defining Empirical Bulk
      Transfer Capacity Metrics" 
      <xref target="RFC3148" />. Other Model Based
      Metrics may cover other applications and transports, such as
      VoIP over UDP and RTP, and new transport protocols.</t>

      <t>The MBM approach, mapping Target Transport Performance to
      a Targeted IP Diagnostic Suite (TIDS) of IP tests, solves
      some intrinsic problems with using TCP or other throughput
      maximizing protocols for measurement. In particular all
      throughput maximizing protocols (and TCP congestion control
      in particular) cause some level of congestion in order to
      detect when they have reached the available capacity 
      limitation of the network. This self inflicted
      congestion obscures the network properties of interest and
      introduces non-linear dynamic equilibrium behaviors that make any
      resulting measurements useless as metrics because they have
      no predictive value for conditions or paths different than
      that of the measurement itself.  In order to prevent these
      effects it is necessary to suppress the effects of TCP congestion 
      control in the measurement method.
      These issues are discussed at length in 
      <xref target="background" />.  Readers whom are unfamiliar with
      basic properties of TCP and TCP-like congestion control may
      find it easier to start at <xref target="background" />
      or <xref target="tcp" />.
</t>

      <t>A Targeted IP Diagnostic Suite does not have such
      difficulties. IP diagnostics can be constructed such that
      they make strong statistical statements about path properties
      that are independent of the measurement details, such as
      vantage and choice of measurement points. Model Based Metrics
      are designed to bridge the gap between empirical IP
      measurements and expected TCP performance for multiple 
      standardized versions of TCP.</t>
      <section title="Version Control">

        <t>RFC Editor: Please remove this entire subsection prior
        to publication.</t>

        <t>Please send comments about this draft to ippm@ietf.org.
        See http://goo.gl/02tkD for more information including:
        interim drafts, an up to date todo list and information on
        contributing.</t>

        <t>Formatted: FORMATTED</t>

	<t>Changes since -10 draft:
	<list style="symbols">
	  <t>A few more nits from various sources.</t>
	  <t>(From IETF LC review comments.)</t>
	  <t>David Mandelberg: design metrics to prevent DDOS.</t>
	  <t>Robert Sparks: Remove all legacy 2119 language.</t>
	  <t>RS: Fixed Xr notation problem.</t>
        </list></t>

	<t>Changes since -09 draft:
	<list style="symbols">
	  <t>Five last minute editing nits.</t>
        </list></t>

	<t>Changes since -08 draft:
	<list style="symbols">
	  <t>Language, spelling and usage nits.</t>
	  <t>Expanded the abstract describe the models.</t>
	  <t>Remove superfluous standards like language</t>  
	  <t>Remove superfluous "future technology" language.</t>
	  <t>Interconnects -> network interconnections.</t>
	  <t>Added more labels to Figure 1.</t>
	  <t>Defined Bulk Transport.</t>
	  <t>Clarified "implied bottleneck IP capacity"</t>
	  <t>Clarified the history of the BTC metrics.</t>
	  <t>Clarified stochastic vs non-stochastic test traffic generation.</t>
	  <t>Reworked Fig 2 and 6.1 "Mimicking slowstart"</t>
	  <t>Described the unsynchronized parallel stream failure case.</t>
	  <t>Discussed how to measure devices that use virtual queues.</t>	
          <t>Changed section 8.5.2 (Streaming Media) to be Passive Measurements.</t>
        </list></t>

	<t>Changes since -07 draft: 
        <list style="symbols">
	  <t>Sharpened the use of "statistical criteria"</t>

	  <t>Sharpened the definition of test_window, and
	  removed related redundant text in several places</t>

	  <t>Clarified "equilibrium" as "dynamic equilibrium,
	  similar to processes observed in chemistry"</t>

	  <t>Properly explained "Heisenberg" as "observer effect"</t>

	  <t>Added the observation from RFC 6576 that HW and SW
	  congestion control implementations do not generally give the
	  same results.</t>

	  <t>Noted that IP and application metrics differ as to how
	  overhead is handled.  MBM is explicit about how it handles
	  overhead.</t>

	  <t>Clarified the language and added a new reference about
	  the problems caused by token bucket policers.</t>

	  <t>Added an subsection in the example that comments on some of
	  issues that need to be mentioned in a future usage or
	  applicability doc.</t>

	  <t>Updated ippm-2680-bis to RFC7680</t>
	  
	  <t>Many terminology, punctuation and spelling nits.</t>
        </list></t>

        <t>Changes since -06 draft: 
        <list style="symbols">

          <t>More language nits:
          <list style="symbols">

            <t>"Targeted IP Diagnostic Suite (TIDS)" replaces
            "Targeted Diagnostic Suite (TDS)".</t>

            <t>"implied bottleneck IP capacity" replaces "implied
            bottleneck IP rate".</t>

            <t>Updated to ECN CE Marks.</t>

            <t>Added "specified temporal structure"</t>

            <t>"test stream" replaces "test traffic"</t>

            <t>"packet transfer" replaces "packet delivery"</t>

            <t>Reworked discussion of slowstart, bursts and
            pacing.</t>

            <t>RFC 7567 replaces RFC 2309.</t>
          </list></t>
        </list></t>

        <t>Changes since -05 draft: 
        <list style="symbols">

          <t>Wordsmithing on sections overhauled in -05 draft.</t>

          <t>Reorganized the document:
          <list style="symbols">

            <t>Relocated subsection "Preconditions".</t>

            <t>Relocated subsection "New Requirements relative to
            RFC 2330".</t>
          </list></t>

          <t>Addressed nits and not so nits by Ruediger Geib.
          (Thanks!)</t>

          <t>Substantially tightened the entire definitions
          section.</t>

          <t>Many terminology changes, to better conform to other
          docs :
          <list style="symbols">

            <t>IP rate and IP capacity (following RFC 5136)
            replaces various forms of link data rate.</t>

            <t>subpath replaces link.</t>

            <t>target_window_size replaces target_pipe_size.</t>

            <t>implied bottleneck IP rate replaces effective
            bottleneck link rate.</t>

            <t>Packet delivery statistics replaces delivery
            statistics.</t>
          </list></t>
        </list></t>

        <t>Changes since -04 draft: 
        <list style="symbols">

          <t>The introduction was heavily overhauled: split into a
          separate introduction and overview.</t>

          <t>The new shorter introduction: 
          <list style="symbols">

            <t>Is a problem statement;</t>

            <t>This document provides a framework;</t>

            <t>That it replaces TCP measurement by IP tests;</t>

            <t>That the results are pass/fail.</t>
          </list></t>

          <t>Added a diagram of the framework to the overview</t>

          <t>and introduces all of the elements of the
          framework.</t>

          <t>Renumbered sections, reducing the depth of some
          section numbers.</t>

          <t>Updated definitions to better agree with other
          documents: 
          <list style="symbols">

            <t>Reordered section 2</t>

            <t>Bulk [data] performance -&gt; Bulk Transport
            Capacity, everywhere including the title.</t>

            <t>loss rate and loss probability -&gt; packet loss
            ratio</t>

            <t>end-to-end path -&gt; complete path</t>

            <t>[end-to-end][target] performance -&gt; Target
            Transport Performance</t>

            <t>load test -&gt; capacity test</t>
          </list></t>
        </list></t>
      </section>
    </section>
