    <section anchor="overview" title="Overview">

      <t>This document describes a modeling framework for deriving
      a Targeted IP Diagnostic Suite from a predetermined Target
      Transport Performance. It is not a complete specification,
      and relies on other standards documents to define important
      details such as packet Type-P selection, sampling techniques,
      vantage selection, etc. We imagine Fully Specified - Targeted
      IP Diagnostic Suites (FS-TIDS), that define all of these
      details. We use Targeted IP Diagnostic Suite (TIDS) to refer
      to the subset of such a specification that is in scope for
      this document.  This terminology is defined in 
      <xref target="terminology" />.</t>

      <t><xref target="background" /> describes some key aspects of TCP
      behavior and what they imply about the requirements for IP
      packet transfer. Most of the IP diagnostic tests needed to
      confirm that the path meets these properties can be built on
      existing IPPM metrics, with the addition of statistical
      criteria for evaluating packet transfer and in a few cases,
      new mechanisms to implement the required temporal structure.
      (One group of tests, the standing queue tests described in 
      <xref target="standing_queue" />, don't correspond to
      existing IPPM metrics, but suitable new IPPM metrics can be patterned
      after the existing definitions.)</t>

      <t><xref target="fig1" /> shows the MBM modeling and measurement
      framework. The Target Transport Performance, at the top of
      the figure, is determined by the needs of the user or
      application, outside the scope of this document. For Bulk
      Transport Capacity, the main performance parameter of
      interest is the Target Data Rate. However, since TCP's
      ability to compensate for less than ideal network conditions
      is fundamentally affected by the Round Trip Time (RTT) and
      the Maximum Transmission Unit (MTU) of the complete path,
      these parameters must also be specified in advance based on
      knowledge about the intended application setting. They may
      reflect a specific application over a real path through the
      Internet or an idealized application and hypothetical path
      representing a typical user community. 
      <xref target="all_models" /> describes the common parameters
      and models derived from the Target Transport Performance.</t>




<!-- 6789112345678921234567893123456789412345678951234567896123456789712 -->
<figure anchor="fig1">
<artwork><![CDATA[
            Target Transport Performance  
  (Target Data Rate, Target RTT and Target MTU)
                         |
                 ________V_________
                 |  mathematical  |
                 |     models     |
                 |                |
                 ------------------
Traffic parameters |            | Statistical criteria
                   |            |
            _______V____________V____Targeted_______
           |       |   * * *    | Diagnostic Suite  |
      _____|_______V____________V________________   |
    __|____________V____________V______________  |  |
    |           IP diagnostic tests            | |  |
    |              |            |              | |  |
    | _____________V__        __V____________  | |  |
    | |   traffic    |        |   Delivery  |  | |  |
    | |   pattern    |        |  Evaluation |  | |  |
    | |  generation  |        |             |  | |  |
    | -------v--------        ------^--------  | |  |
    |   |    v    test stream via   ^      |   | |--
    |   |  -->======================>--    |   | |
    |   |       subpath under test         |   |-
    ----V----------------------------------V--- |
        | |  |                             | |  |
        V V  V                             V V  V
    fail/inconclusive            pass/fail/inconclusive  
(traffic generation status)           (test result)  
]]></artwork>
<postamble>Overall Modeling Framework</postamble></figure>

      <t>Mathematical TCP models are used to determine Traffic 
	  parameters and subsequently to design traffic
      patterns that mimic TCP or other transport protocol
      delivering bulk data and operating at the Target Data Rate,
      MTU and RTT over a full range of conditions, including flows
      that are bursty at multiple time scales. The traffic patterns
      are generated based on the three Target parameters of
      complete path and independent of the properties of individual
      subpaths using the techniques described in 
      <xref target="generation" />. As much as possible the
      test streams are generated deterministically
      (precomputed) to minimize the extent to which test
      methodology, measurement points, measurement vantage or path
      partitioning affect the details of the measurement
      traffic.</t>

      <t>
      <xref target="results" /> describes packet transfer statistics
      and methods to test them against the statistical criteria provided by the
      mathematical models. Since the statistical criteria typically
      apply to the complete path (a composition of subpaths)
      <xref target="RFC6049" />, in situ testing requires that the
      end-to-end statistical criteria be apportioned as separate
      criteria for each subpath. Subpaths that are expected to be
      bottlenecks would then be permitted to contribute a larger
      fraction of the end-to-end
      packet loss budget. In compensation,
      subpaths that are not expected to exhibit bottlenecks must be constrained to contribute less packet
      loss. Thus the statistical criteria for each subpath in each test of a
      TIDS is an apportioned share of the end-to-end statistical criteria
      for the complete path which was determined by the mathematical model.
      </t>

      <t>
      <xref target="tests" /> describes the suite of individual
      tests needed to verify all of required IP delivery
      properties. A subpath passes if and only if all of the
      individual IP diagnostic tests pass. Any subpath that fails
      any test indicates that some users are likely to fail to attain
      their Target Transport Performance under some conditions. In
      addition to passing or failing, a test can be deemed to be
      inconclusive for a number of reasons including: the
      precomputed traffic pattern was not accurately generated; the
      measurement results were not statistically significant; and
      others such as failing to meet some required test
      preconditions. If all tests pass but some are
      inconclusive, then the entire suite is deemed to be
      inconclusive.</t>

      <t>In 
      <xref target="examples" /> we present an example TIDS that
      might be representative of High Definition (HD) video, and illustrate how Model
      Based Metrics can be used to address difficult measurement
      situations, such as confirming that inter-carrier exchanges
      have sufficient performance and capacity to deliver HD video
      between ISPs.</t>

      <t>Since there is some uncertainty in the modeling process, 
      <xref target="validation" /> describes a validation procedure
      to diagnose and minimize false positive and false negative
      results.</t>
      <!--

<t>A TIDS includes the target parameters, documentation of the models and assumptions used to derive the IP diagnostic test parameters, specifications for the traffic patterns and packet transfer statistics for the tests themselves, and a description of a test setup that can be used to validate the tests and models.</t>
-->
    </section>
