      <section anchor="paced" title="Mimicking slowstart">

        <t>TCP slowstart has a two level burst structure as shown
        in 
        <xref target="fig2" />. The fine time structure is caused
	by efficiency algorithms that deliberately batch work
	(CPU, channel allocation, etc) to better amortize
	certain network and host overheads.
	ACKs passing through the return path
        typically cause the sender to transmit small bursts of data at
        full sender interface rate.
	For example TCP Segmentation Offload (TSO) and Delayed
	Acknowledgment both contribute to this effect.
	During slowstart these bursts are
	at the same headway as the
        returning ACKs, but are typically twice as large (e.g.
	having twice as much data) as the ACK
        reported was delivered to the receiver. Due to variations
        in delayed ACK and algorithms such as Appropriate Byte
        Counting 
        <xref target="RFC3465" />, different pairs of senders and
        receivers produce slightly different burst patterns. Without loss of
        generality, we assume each ACK causes 4 packet sender interface rate bursts at an
        average headway equal to the ACK headway, and corresponding
        to sending at an average rate equal to twice the effective
        bottleneck IP rate.  Each slowstart burst consists of a series of
	4 packet sender interface rate bursts such that the total number of packets
	is the current window size (as of the last packet in the burst).</t>

        <t>The coarse time structure is due to each RTT being a
	reflection of the prior RTT.
        For real transport protocols,
	each slowstart burst is twice as
        large (twice the window) as the previous burst but is
	spread out in time by the network bottleneck, such that each successive RTT
	exhibits the same effective bottleneck IP rate.
	The slowstart phase ends on the first lost packet or ECN mark, which is
	intended to happen after successive slowstart bursts merge:
	the next burst starts before the bottleneck queue is fully drained
	and the prior burst is complete.</t>

	<t>For diagnostic tests
        described below we preserve the fine time structure but
        manipulate the coarse structure of the slowstart bursts
	(burst size and headway) to measure the
        ability of the dominant bottleneck to absorb and smooth
        slowstart bursts.</t>

        <t>Note that a stream of repeated slowstart bursts has
        three different average rates, depending on the averaging
        time interval. At the finest time scale (a few packet times at
        the sender interface) the peak of the average IP rate is
        the same as the sender interface rate; at a medium
        timescale (a few ACK times at the dominant bottleneck)
        the peak of the average IP rate is twice the implied
        bottleneck IP capacity; and at time scales longer than the
        target_RTT and when the burst size is equal to the
        target_window_size the average rate is equal to the
        target_data_rate. This pattern corresponds to repeating the
        last RTT of TCP slowstart when delayed ACK and sender side
        byte counting are present but without the limits specified
        in Appropriate Byte Counting 
        <xref target="RFC3465" />.</t>
        <!-- 6789112345678921234567893123456789412345678951234567896123456789712 -->
        <figure anchor="fig2">
          <artwork>
            <![CDATA[
time ==>    ( - equals one packet)

Fine time structure of the packet stream:
 
----  ----  ----  ----  ----
|<>| sender interface rate bursts (typically 3 or 4 packets)
|<===>| burst headway (from the ACK headway)

\____repeating sender______/
       rate bursts


Coarse (RTT level) time structure of the packet stream:
----  ----  ----  ----  ----                     ----  ---- ...
|<========================>| slowstart burst size (from the window) 
|<==============================================>| slowstart headway
                                                    (from the RTT)
\___one slowstart burst____/                     \_________ ...
                                           Repeated slowstart bursts
]]></artwork>
<postamble>Multiple levels of Slowstart Bursts</postamble>
</figure>
      </section>
