      <section anchor="paced" title="Mimicking slowstart">

        <t>TCP slowstart has a two level burst structure as shown
        in 
        <xref target="fig2" />. The fine structure is caused by the
        interaction between the ACK clock and TCP efficiency
        algorithms. Each ACK passing through the return path
        triggers a small data burst. These bursts are typically
        full sender interface rate, with the same headway as the
        returning ACKs, but having twice as much data as the ACK
        reported was delivered to the receiver. Due to variations
        in delayed ACK and algorithms such as Appropriate Byte
        Counting 
        <xref target="RFC3465" />, different pairs of senders and
        receivers produce different burst patterns. Without loss of
        generality, we assume each ACK causes 4 packet bursts at an
        average headway equal to the ACK headway, and corresponding
        to sending at an average rate equal to twice the effective
        bottleneck IP rate. This fine structure defines one
        slowstart rate burst.</t>

        <t>For a transport protocol the slowstart bursts are
        repeated every target_RTT. Each slowstart burst is twice as
        large as the previous burst, and slowstart ends on the
        first lost packet or ECN mark. For diagnostic tests
        described below we preserve the fine structure but
        manipulate the burst size and headway to measure the
        ability of the dominant bottleneck to absorb and smooth
        slowstart bursts.</t>

        <t>Note that a stream of repeated slowstart bursts has
        three different average rates, depending on the averaging
        interval. At the finest time scale (a few packet times at
        the sender interface) the peak of the average IP rate is
        the same as the sender interface rate; at a medium
        timescale (a few packet times at the dominant bottleneck)
        the peak of the average IP rate is twice the implied
        bottleneck IP capacity; and at time scales longer than the
        target_RTT and when the burst size is equal to the
        target_window_size the average rate is equal to the
        target_data_rate. This pattern corresponds to repeating the
        last RTT of TCP slowstart when delayed ACK and sender side
        byte counting are present but without the limits specified
        in Appropriate Byte Counting 
        <xref target="RFC3465" />.</t>
        <!-- 6789112345678921234567893123456789412345678951234567896123456789712 -->
        <figure anchor="fig2">
          <artwork>
            <![CDATA[
time ==>    ( - equals one packet)
Packet stream:
 
----  ----  ----  ----  ----                     ----  ---- ... 
  
|<>| sender interface rate bursts (typically 3 or 4 packets)
|<===>| burst headway (determined by ACK headway)
|<========================>| slowstart burst size(from the window) 
|<==============================================>| slowstart headway
\____________ _____________/                     \______ __ ...
             V                                          V
      One slowstart burst                   Repeated slowstart bursts
]]></artwork>
<postamble>Multiple levels of Slowstart Bursts</postamble>
</figure>
      </section>
