      <section anchor="reordering" title="Reordering Tolerance">

        <t>All tests must be instrumented for packet level
        reordering 
        <xref target="RFC4737" />. However, there is no consensus
        for how much reordering should be acceptable. Over the last
        two decades the general trend has been to make protocols
        and applications more tolerant to reordering (see for
        example 
        <xref target="RFC4015" />), in response to the gradual
        increase in reordering in the network. This increase has
        been due to the deployment of technologies such as
	multithreaded routing lookups and Equal Cost MultiPath (ECMP)
        routing. These techniques increase parallelism in network
        and are critical to enabling overall Internet growth to
        exceed Moore's Law.</t>

        <t>Note that transport retransmission strategies can trade
        off reordering tolerance vs how quickly they can repair
        losses vs overhead from spurious retransmissions. In
        advance of new retransmission strategies we propose the
        following strawman: Transport protocols should be able to
        adapt to reordering as long as the reordering extent is not
        more than the maximum of one quarter window or 1 mS,
        whichever is larger.  (These values come from experience
	prototyping Early Retransmit <xref target="RFC5827" /> and
	related algorithms. They agree with the values being proposed
	for "RACK: a time-based fast loss detection
	algorithm" <xref target="I-D.ietf-tcpm-rack" />.)
	Within this limit on reorder extent,
        there should be no bound on reordering density.</t>

        <t>By implication, recording which is less than these
        bounds should not be treated as a network impairment.
        However 
        <xref target="RFC4737" /> still applies: reordering should
        be instrumented and the maximum reordering that can be
        properly characterized by the test (because of the bound on history
        buffers) should be recorded with the measurement
        results.</t>

        <t>Reordering tolerance and diagnostic limitations, such as
        the size of the history buffer used to diagnose packets
        that are way out-of-order, must be specified in a
        FSTIDS.</t>
        <!--

<t>Section 5 of <xref target="RFC4737" /> proposed a metric that may be sufficient to designate isolated reordered packets as effectively lost, because TCP's retransmission response would be the same.</t>

-->
      </section>
