      <section anchor="scanned_window"
      title="Scanned window pseudo CBR">

        <t>Scanned window pseudo CBR is similar to the constant
        window CBR described above, except the window is scanned
        across a range of sizes designed to include two key events,
        the onset of queueing and the onset of packet loss or ECN
        CE marks. The window is scanned by incrementing it by one
        packet every 2*target_window_size delivered packets. This
        mimics the additive increase phase of standard Reno TCP
        congestion avoidance when delayed ACKs are in effect.
        Normally the window increases separated by intervals
        slightly longer than twice the target_RTT.</t>

        <t>There are two ways to implement this test: one built by
        applying a window clamp to standard congestion control in a
        standard protocol such as TCP and the other built by
        stiffening a non-standard transport protocol. When standard
        congestion control is in effect, any losses or ECN CE marks
        cause the transport to revert to a window smaller than the
        clamp such that the scanning clamp loses control the window
        size. The NPAD pathdiag tool is an example of this class of
        algorithms 
        <xref target="Pathdiag" />.</t>

        <t>Alternatively a non-standard congestion control
        algorithm can respond to losses by transmitting extra data,
        such that it maintains the specified window size
        independent of losses or ECN CE marks. Such a stiffened
        transport explicitly violates mandatory Internet congestion
        control 
        <xref target="RFC5681" /> and is not suitable for in situ
        testing. It is only appropriate for engineering testing
        under laboratory conditions. The Windowed Ping tool
        implements such a test 
        <xref target="WPING" />. The tool described in the paper
        has been updated.<xref target="mpingSource" /></t>

        <t>The test procedures in 
        <xref target="standing_queue" /> describe how to the
        partition the scans into regions and how to interpret the
        results.</t>
      </section>
