      <section anchor="score" title="Test outcomes">

        <t>To perform an exhaustive test of a complete network
        path, each test of the TIDS is applied to each subpath of
        the complete path. If any subpath fails any test then a
        standard transport protocol running over the complete path
        can also be expected to fail to attain the Target Transport
        Performance under some conditions.</t>

        <t>In addition to passing or failing, a test can be deemed
        to be inconclusive for a number of reasons. Proper
        instrumentation and treatment of inconclusive outcomes is
        critical to the accuracy and robustness of Model Based
        Metrics. Tests can be inconclusive if the precomputed
        traffic pattern or data rates were not accurately
        generated; the measurement results were not statistically
        significant; and others causes such as failing to meet some
        required preconditions for the test. See 
        <xref target="qualifications" /></t>

        <t>For example consider a test that implements Constant
        Window Pseudo CBR (<xref target="constant_window" />)
	by adding rate controls
        and detailed IP packet transfer instrumentation to TCP
        (e.g. 
        <xref target="RFC4898" />). TCP includes built in control
        systems which might interfere with the sending data rate.
        If such a test meets the required packet transfer
        statistics (e.g. run length) while failing to attain the
        specified data rate it must be treated as an inconclusive
        result, because we can not a priori determine if the
        reduced data rate was caused by a TCP problem or a network
        problem, or if the reduced data rate had a material effect
        on the observed packet transfer statistics.</t>

        <t>Note that for capacity tests, if the observed packet
        transfer statistics meet the statistical criteria for
        failing (accepting hypnosis H1 in 
        <xref target="statistics" />), the test can can be
        considered to have failed because it doesn't really matter
        that the test didn't attain the required data rate.</t>

        <t>The really important new properties of MBM, such as
        vantage independence, are a direct consequence of opening
        the control loops in the protocols, such that the test
        stream does not depend on network conditions or IP packets
        received. Any mechanism that introduces feedback between
        the path's measurements and the test stream generation is
        at risk of introducing non-linearities that spoil these
        properties. Any exceptional event that indicates that such
        feedback has happened should cause the test to be
        considered inconclusive.</t>

        <t>One way to view inconclusive tests is that they reflect
        situations where a test outcome is ambiguous between
        limitations of the network and some unknown limitation of
        the IP diagnostic test itself, which may have been caused
        by some uncontrolled feedback from the network.</t>

        <t>Note that procedures that attempt to search the target
        parameter space to find the limits on some parameter such
        as target_data_rate are at risk of breaking the location
        independent properties of Model Based Metrics, if any part
        of the boundary between passing and inconclusive or failing
	results is
        sensitive to RTT (which is normally the case).  For example
	the maximum date rate for a margional link (e.g.
	exhibiting excess errors) is likely to be sensitive to the
	test path RTT.  The maximum observed data rate over the test
	path has very little predictive value for the maximum rate over a
	different path.
	</t>

        <t>One of the goals for evolving TIDS designs will be to
        keep sharpening distinction between inconclusive, passing
        and failing tests. The criteria for for passing, failing
        and inconclusive tests MUST be explicitly stated for every
        test in the TIDS or FSTIDS.</t>

        <t>One of the goals of evolving the testing process,
        procedures, tools and measurement point selection should be
        to minimize the number of inconclusive tests.</t>

        <t>It may be useful to keep raw packet transfer statistics
        and ancillary metrics 
        <xref target="RFC3148" /> for deeper study of the behavior
        of the network path and to measure the tools themselves.
        Raw packet transfer statistics can help to drive tool
        evolution. Under some conditions it might be possible to
        re-evaluate the raw data for satisfying alternate Target
        Transport Performance. However it is important to guard
        against sampling bias and other implicit feedback which can
        cause false results and exhibit measurement point vantage
        sensitivity. Simply applying different delivery criteria
        based on a different Target Transport Performance is
        insufficient if the test traffic patterns (bursts, etc.)
        does not match the alternate Target Transport
        Performance.</t>
      </section>
