      <section anchor="standing_queue"
      title="Standing Queue Tests">

        <t>These engineering tests confirm that the bottleneck is
        well behaved across the onset of packet loss, which
        typically follows after the onset of queueing. Well behaved
        generally means lossless for transient queues, but once the
        queue has been sustained for a sufficient period of time
        (or reaches a sufficient queue depth) there should be a
        small number of losses to signal to the transport protocol
        that it should reduce its window. Losses that are too early
        can prevent the transport from averaging at the
        target_data_rate. Losses that are too late indicate that
        the queue might be subject to bufferbloat 
        <xref target="wikiBloat" /> and inflict excess queuing
        delays on all flows sharing the bottleneck queue. Excess
        losses (more than half of the window) at the onset of
        congestion make loss recovery problematic for the transport
        protocol. Non-linear, erratic or excessive RTT increases
        suggest poor interactions between the channel acquisition
        algorithms and the transport self clock. All of the tests
        in this section use the same basic scanning algorithm,
        described here, but score the link or subpath on the basis
        of how well it avoids each of these problems.</t>

        <t>For some technologies the data might not be subject to
        increasing delays, in which case the data rate will vary
        with the window size all the way up to the onset of load
        induced packet loss or ECN CE marks. For theses
        technologies, the discussion of queueing does not apply,
        but it is still required that the onset of losses or ECN CE
        marks be at an appropriate point and progressive.</t>

        <t>Use the procedure in 
        <xref target="scanned_window" /> to sweep the window across
        the onset of queueing and the onset of loss. The tests
        below all assume that the scan emulates standard additive
        increase and delayed ACK by incrementing the window by one
        packet for every 2*target_window_size packets delivered. A
        scan can typically be divided into three regions: below the
        onset of queueing, a standing queue, and at or beyond the
        onset of loss.</t>

        <t>Below the onset of queueing the RTT is typically fairly
        constant, and the data rate varies in proportion to the
        window size. Once the data rate reaches the subpath IP
        rate, the data rate becomes fairly constant, and the RTT
        increases in proportion to the increase in window size. The
        precise transition across the start of queueing can be
        identified by the maximum network power, defined to be the
        ratio data rate over the RTT. The network power can be
        computed at each window size, and the window with the
        maximum are taken as the start of the queueing region.</t>

        <t>For technologies that do not have conventional queues,
        start the scan at a window equal to the
        test_window=target_data_rate*test_path_RTT/target_MTU, i.e.
        starting at the target rate, instead of the power
        point.</t>

        <t>If there is random background loss (e.g. bit errors,
        etc), precise determination of the onset of queue induced
        packet loss may require multiple scans. Above the onset of
        queuing loss, all transport protocols are expected to
        experience periodic losses determined by the interaction
        between the congestion control and AQM algorithms. For
        standard congestion control algorithms the periodic losses
        are likely to be relatively widely spaced and the details
        are typically dominated by the behavior of the transport
        protocol itself. For the stiffened transport protocols case
        (with non-standard, aggressive congestion control
        algorithms) the details of periodic losses will be
        dominated by how the the window increase function responds
        to loss. 
        <!-- One more sentence @@ --></t>
#include src/congestion_avoidance.xml
#include src/buffer_bloat.xml
#include src/excessive.xml
#include src/self_interference.xml
      </section>
