        <section anchor="sustained_burst"
        title="Sustained Bursts Test">

          <t>The sustained burst test implements a combined worst
          case version of all of the capacity tests above. It is
          simply:</t>

          <t>Send target_window_size bursts of packets at server
          interface rate with target_RTT burst headway (burst start
          to next burst start). Verify that the observed packet transfer
          statistics meets the target_run_length.</t>

          <t>Key observations:
          <list style="symbols">

            <t>The subpath under test is expected to go idle for
            some fraction of the time:
            (subpath_IP_capacity-target_rate/target_MTU-header_overhead*target_MTU)/subpath_IP_capacity.
            Failing to do so indicates a problem with the procedure
            and an inconclusive test result.</t>
@@@@@ Not sure about this, does  a sub-path with CBR rate shaper (at target_rate)
comply with the equation above? or does it require derating as below?
(I guess that an extremely short idle time would satisfy this expectation.)
One set of parens is unnecessary, too. ]

            <t>The burst sensitivity can be derated by sending
            smaller bursts more frequently. E.g. send
            target_window_size*derate packet bursts every
            target_RTT*derate.</t>
@@@@@ Derate is a factor less than 1, correct?  is this in the definition?

            <t>When not derated, this test is the most strenuous
            capacity test.</t>

            <t>A subpath that passes this test is likely to be able
            to sustain higher rates (close to subpath_IP_capacity)
            for paths with RTTs significantly smaller than the
            target_RTT.</t>

            <t>This test can be implemented with instrumented TCP 
            <xref target="RFC4898" />, using a specialized
            measurement application at one end 
            <xref target="MBMSource" /> and a minimal service at the
            other end 
            <xref target="RFC0863" />
            <xref target="RFC0864" />.</t>

            <t>This test is efficient to implement, since it does
            not require per-packet timers, and can make use of TSO
            in modern NIC hardware.</t>

            <t>If a subpath is known to pass the Standing Queue
            engineering tests (particularly that it has a
            progressive onset of loss at an appropriate queue
            depth), then the Sustained Burst Test is sufficient to
            assure that the subpath under test will not impair Bulk
            Transport Capacity at the target performance under all
            conditions. See 
            <xref target="standing_queue" /> for a discussion of the
            standing queue tests.</t>
          </list></t>

          <t>Note that this test is clearly independent of the
          subpath RTT, or other details of the measurement
          infrastructure, as long as the measurement infrastructure
          can accurately and reliably deliver the required bursts
          to the subpath under test.</t>
        </section>
