      <section anchor="target"
      title="Target End-to-end parameters">

        <t>The target end-to-end parameters are the Target Data
        Rate, Target RTT and Target MTU as defined in 
        <xref target="terminology" />. These parameters are
        determined by the needs of the application or the ultimate
        end user and the complete Internet path over which the
        application is expected to operate. The target parameters
        are in units that make sense to upper layers: payload bytes
        delivered to the application, above TCP. They exclude
        overheads associated with TCP and IP headers, retransmits
        and other protocols (e.g. DNS). Note that IP-based network 
        services include TCP headers and retransmissions as part of 
        delivered payload, and this difference is recognized in 
        calculations below (header_overhead). </t>

        <t>Other end-to-end parameters defined in 
        <xref target="terminology" /> include the effective
        bottleneck data rate, the sender interface data rate and
        the TCP and IP header sizes.</t>

        <t>The target_data_rate must be smaller than all subpath IP
        capacities by enough headroom to carry the transport
        protocol overhead, explicitly including retransmissions and
        an allowance for fluctuations in TCP's actual data rate.
        Specifying a target_data_rate with insufficient headroom is
        likely to result in brittle measurements having little
        predictive value.</t>

        <t>Note that the target parameters can be specified for a
        hypothetical path, for example to construct TIDS designed
        for bench testing in the absence of a real application; or
        for a live in situ test of production infrastructure.</t>

        <t>The number of concurrent connections is explicitly not a
        parameter to this model. If a subpath requires multiple
        connections in order to meet the specified performance,
        that must be stated explicitly and the procedure described
        in 
        <xref target="channelized" /> applies.</t>
      </section>
